Josh Wessel . Jarvis Consulting

I graduated from Ontario Tech University with a Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology, majoring in Game Development and Entrepreneurship. During my time at university, I learned languages such as C++, C#, and R, using IDE's such as Visual Studio and RStudio. I was introduced to concepts such as object oriented programming, user research and algorithms & data structures. I used source control tools such as Git, GitHub, and GitKraken, and other collaboration tools such as Discord & Trello. I was also given the opportunity to use the agile framework in the form of daily scrum meetings. For the three summers from 2018-2020, I worked as an Environmental Intern; the first two summers for Sustainable Cobourg, and the third summer for the Township of Hamilton. My responsibilities included research, data collection, data entry, and data visualization. These summer positions also provided opportunities for me to develop my organization, communication, and time management skills. I am passionate about collecting and organizing data. As a result, I am interested in pursuing a career in the data industry.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Agile/Scrum, C++, Object Oriented Programming, Visual Studio

Competent: Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Git, C#, R, tidyverse Familiar: Docker, PostgreSQL, RStudio, GitKraken, Tableau

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng JoshWessel

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Developed a system that collects hardware specifications and resource usage data from Linux hosts and sends it to a PostgreSQL database. The system is built on Linux using SQL and bash scripts. Docker is used to create and manage the container in which the system runs. Crontab automates the collection of usage data from the host device by running the appropriate script every minute while the system is active. Finally, the queried data addresses various questions related to the hardware information and usage data in the PostgreSQL database.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App:
- JDBC App:
- Grep App: Developed an application that searches all files within a given directory for all lines that match a given pattern, writing all matches to a given output location. The application requires the user to supply three parameters. These parameters include a pattern to search for, the search directory, and the output file to store all matched lines. The application was written in Java, using IntelliJ as the IDE. The testing process involved a series of trial and error tests. IntelliJ's debugger was especially useful in identifying issues related to properly searching the given directory. The application was cleaned and packaged using Maven and deployed using Docker. A Docker image was also built and pushed to Docker Hub.

Highlighted Projects

Babsketball (2021) [GitHub]: Developed a text-based basketball simulation game featuring an assortment of mistake-prone basketball players called Babduls. The program is written using C++ in Visual Studio and uses object-oriented programming.

Firefighter Simulator (2020): Developed a first-person firefighting simulator where the user controls a firefighter and must extinguish all fires in a burning building. The simulation is built in the Unity game engine and uses C# scripts.

Defleation (2018): Developed a top-down side scroller game written using C++ and the Cocos2d-x game engine in Visual Studio.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-Present): Developed applications using languages such as bash, SQL, and Java, as well as software such as Google Cloud Platform, IntelliJ, Maven, and Docker to gain experience in data engineering. Used agile framework (daily scrum meetings and bi-weekly sprint retrospective meetings) to complete projects.

Environmental Intern, Sustainable Cobourg (2018-2019 (Summers)): Summer position as an environmental intern working for Sustainable Cobourg. My responsibilities included research, data collection, data entry, and creating

charts and graphs. Technologies used include Google Suite, Microsoft Office, and a web-based framework that functioned as a database, in which I performed data entry (in the second summer). Working alone allowed me the opportunity to improve my time management skills. I was often given a list of tasks and then left to complete them myself, allowing me the opportunity to practice effective time management. I was also able to use my organizational skills while working with a large number of files and folders on a daily basis.

Environmental Intern, Hamilton Township (2020 (Summer)): Summer position as an environmental intern working for Hamilton Township. My specific responsibilities included research, data collection, data entry, creating charts and graphs, and survey creation. Technologies used include Google Suite, Microsoft Office, and a web-based framework that functioned as a database, in which I performed data entry. This position was entirely remote, which allowed me to develop my communication skills using communication tools such as email and zoom. Working alone also allowed me the opportunity to improve my time management skills. I was often given a list of tasks and then left to complete them myself, allowing me the opportunity to practice effective time management. I was also able to use my organizational skills while working with a large number of files and folders on a daily basis.

Education

Ontario Tech University (2017-2021), Bachelor of Information Technology, Game Development And Entrepreneurship - Ontario Tech University Entry Scholarship for averaging 90% to 95% in top 6 high school courses - Dean's List (2020-2021)

Miscellaneous

- Dean's List (2020-2021)
- Rotary Club of Northumberland Sunrise Scholarship for high academic standing
- Developing video games